Guide to the Rice Public Art records, 2011-2015 UA 358
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice Public Art records
2011-2015
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 358
7 Linear Feet 6 boxes
0.699 Gigabytes UA0358aip_001, UA0358aip_002
This collection includes publicity, ephemera, dedication event photos and more, related to works of art on the Rice University campus.
Biographical / Historical
Rice Public Art at Rice University oversees the selection and installation of public artworks on campus.
Scope and Contents
This material includes publicity, ephemera, dedication event photos and more, related to works of art on the Rice University campus. The James Turrell skyspace known as "Twilight Epiphany" is particularly well represented here.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection open for research without restrictions, except for materials in Series III: Addendum, which is restricted from all viewing and use until 2050. Restricted materials are noted in the finding aid.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred by Rice Public Art, via Caroline Walker, in 2015 with an addenda in 2020.
Index Terms
Subjects
Arts -- Texas; Sculpture, American; Universities and colleges
Places
Art
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University
- Series I. James Turrell Skyspace printed material and ephemera, 213663
  - Suzanne Deal Booth interview, pre-2012 (DVD / video), 260490 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dedication logistics and ephemera, 2012, 260493 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Artworks by Beeville ISD's Moreno Middle School students, inspired by Twilight Epiphany, 2012-2013, 260497 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ephemera, undated, 260509 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Turrell: Events At The Skyspace, 2013, 213664 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Turrell: ArtsInsight Documentary, 213665 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Turrell: Press and Publications 2012, 213666 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Turrell: Press and Publications 2013, 213668 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Turrell: Press and Publications 2014, 213669 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Turrell: Press and Publications 2015, 213670 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Turrell: Letters to Suzanne Deal Booth, 213671 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Series II. Rice Public Art, 213672
  - Maps of Rice Public Art, 213673 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - ArtsInsight Documentary: Gunilla Kingberg/Rice Art, 213675 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - BRC pop-up gallery installation, Ayako Ono (images), 2013-07; 260512 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Scope and Contents
    The digital object for this file contains simple born-digital jpg image files taken at this event.
  - Edgar Odell Lovett statue, dedication and breakfast, Oct. 13, 2012 (images), 260534 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    The digital object for this file contains simple born-digital jpg images of the statue dedication event.
  - Lino Tagliapietra news articles, 2004-2007, 260562 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Calendar of Events, Spring 2014, 260563 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Charles Mary Kubricht "paraMuseum: Environmental Exigencies" card, undated, 260565 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Opening Reception Invitations, 213674 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series III. Rice Public Art records addendum, 2020
  - Budgets [Restricted] (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Series A: Committee [Restricted] (Box 3, Folder 2-14)
    - 2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 2002 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 2006 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 2007 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 2008 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 2009 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 2010 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 2011 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 2012 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 2013 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 2014 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 2015 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Development (1/5) [Restricted] (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Development (2/5) [Restricted] (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Development (3/5) [Restricted] (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Development (4/5) [Restricted] (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Development (5/5) [Restricted] (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - History (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Object Files: General, 1968-2012 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Object Files: Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
  - Objects: Pre-Columbian (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Programming (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Proposals (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Proposals: Highstein, Jene (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Proposals: Kaneko, Jun (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Proposals: Kendrick, Mel (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Proposals: Lobe, Robert (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Proposals: Stockholder, Jessica (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Proposals: Von Rydingsvard, Ursula (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Strategic Planning [Restricted] (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series B: Public Art Installations
    - Barrera, Debra (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Berlin Wall (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Berlin Wall: Photos of Installation at Rice, 1991, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - BRC Pop-up Gallery, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Clement, John (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Dashwood, Geoffrey, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Dean, Stephen (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - di Suvero, Mark, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Frankfort, Dana, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Havel, Joseph, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Heizer, Michael, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Henry, John, 2016 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Hood, Dorothy, 2016-2017 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Kubricht, Charles Mary, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Milles, Carl, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Moroles, Jesus, 2016 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Plensa, Jaume, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Robson, Aurora, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Surls, James, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Tagliapietra, Lino, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Villareal, Leo, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Wolfe, Bruce, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Rice University Art Gallery Exhibitions (1/2), 1995-2011 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Rice University Art Gallery Exhibitions (2/2), 1995-2011 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Sub-Series C: Rice Gallery Exhibitions
    - Nicole Eisenman - Behavior, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Shout Outs, 1999-11-04-1999-12-12 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Wolfgang Winter / Berthold Horbelt - Kastenhaus, 2000-09-22-2000-10-29 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Martha Burgess - Manly on the Plaid, 2000-11-09-2000-12-17 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Karim Rashid - Pleasurscape, 2001-01-25-2001-02-25 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Jennifer Steinkamp & Jimmy Johnson - One Saw; The Other Saw, 2001-09-21-2001-10-28 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Shigeru Ban - Bamboo Roof, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Lee Ming Wei - The Tourist Project, 2002-01-17-2002-02-24 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Adriana Arenas Ilian - The Precious Stone & Gold Factory, 2002-03-08-2002-04-14 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Ester Partegas - Samesation, 2002-09-20-2002-10-27 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Phoebe Washburn - True, False, and Slightly Better, 2003-01-24-2003-03-23 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Heather Ackroyd & Dan Harvey - Green Brick, Green Black, 2004-01-22-2004-02-29 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Jessica Stockholder - Sam Ran Over Sand, 2004-09-16-2004-10-31 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Allen Ruppersberg - The Singing Posters, 2004-11-11-2004-12-12 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Jacob Hashimoto - Superabundant Atmosphere, 2005-03-17-2005-04-17 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Diane Landry, 2005-09-22-2005-10-30 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Matthew White & Frank Webb - Eminent Domain, 2005-11-10-2005-12-11 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - David Ellis - conversation, 2006-01-19-2006-03-05 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Benjamin Ball & Gaston Nogres - Rip Curl Canyon, 2006-09-21-2006-10-29 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - John Cerney - Big Landscape, Big West, 2006-11-09-2006-12-10 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Judy Pfaff - All of the Above, 2007-02-01-2007-04-01 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Kirsten Hassenfeld - Dans la Lune, 2007-09-27-2007-12-09 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Charlie Roberts - Mambo Jambo: Cabinet of the Cosmos, 2008-01-24-2008-03-30 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Aurora Robson - The Great Indoors, 2008-09-18-2008-10-26 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Michael a. Salter - Too Much, 2008-11-06-2008-12-14 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Paul Villinski - Emergency Response Studio, 2009-01-29-2010-03-01 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Henrique Oliveira - Tapumes, 2009-03-26-2009-08-11 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Wayne White - Big Lectric Fan to Keep Me Cool While I Sleep, 2009-09-10-2009-12-13 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - El Anatsui - Gli, 2010-01-28-2010-03-14 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Andrea Dezso - Sometimes in My Dreams I Fly, 2010-04-08-2010-08-08 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Sarah Oppenheimer - D-17, 2010-09-16-2010-12-05 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Ana Serrano - Salon of Beuty, 2011-09-29-2011-12-11 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Joel Shapiro - Untitled, 2012-02-02-2012-03-18 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Yasuaki Onishi - Reverse of Volume RG, 2012-04-13-2012-07-27 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Gunilla Klingberg - Wheel of Everyday Life, 2013-01-31-2013-03-17 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Soo Sunny Park - Unwoven Light, 2013-04-11-2013-08-30 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Peter Brotzmann - Graphic Design Work (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - El Ultimo Grito - Garden Object, 2014-01-23-2014-03-16 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Dinh Q. LE - Crossing the Farther Shore, 2014-04-10-2014-08-28 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Yusuke Asai - Yamatane, 2014-10-21-2014-11-11 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Jane Miller - Got a Minute?, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Art Lab Zine, 2013, 2013, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Rice School of Architecture Spotlight Program, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Shepherd School of Music Programs (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - VADA (Visual and Dramatic Arts) Emergency Room Programs, 2010-2014 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Sub-Series D: Turrell Skyspace
    - Art Agreement: Skyspace Acquisition (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Confidential [Restricted] (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Construction Meetings (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Docents: Archived Student Docents [Restricted] (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Docents: Archived Student Docent Forms [Restricted] (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Docents: Current Docents [Restricted] (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Documents (miscellaneous) (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Early Plans (1/2) (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Early Plans (2/2) (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Policy Table of Contents (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Pre-construction Services Proposal: Bellows, 2009-08-18 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Pre-construction Services Proposal: Harvey, 2009-08-18 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Pre-construction Services Proposal: Linbeck, 2009-08-18 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Pre-design Report, 2009-08-11-2010-05-19 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Project Book (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Skyspace Programming (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Renovations, 2018 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Rentals (Private) Data (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Rentals [Restricted] (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Shows, 2017-2018 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - VIP Dedication Final Docs (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Website Templates (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Sub-Series E: Oversize
    - Thorsten Brinkman - "The Great Cape Rinderhorn" Poster, 2016-02-04-2016-05-15 (Box 6)
    - Rice University Art Gallery Exhibitions 1995-2011 Poster (Box 6)
    - Artforum Skyspace Magazine articles (Box 6)
    - Artdesk Booklets, featuring Skyspace, Spring 2017 (Box 6)